Samnoon Haider

Software Engineer

Phone: 978-496-6357 | Email: Samnoon.Haider@gmail.com | Location: Atlanta, GA

SUMMARY

I'm a software engineer with extensive experience working with JavaScript, React, and Node.js. I enjoy building intuitive user interfaces that deliver real value to users. With a background in business and project management, I have tremendous empathy for users and am very much product and UX-oriented. I'm passionate about diverse teams coming together to make a positive impact and having fun along the way.

WEBSITES

Portfolio: samnoonhaider.com

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/samnoon-haider

Github: github.com/sam-haider **Blog:** blog.samnoonhaider.com

EDUCATION

HarvardX - Certificate, CS50 – Intro to Computer Science Remote | 2020 - 2020

General Assembly - Software Engineering Immersive Program Boston, MA | 2019 - 2019

University of Connecticut - B.S., Business Administration Storrs, CT | 2006 - 2010

SKILLS

Languages: Proficient in JavaScript, Typescript, Python, HTML, CSS; Experience with C, Ruby

Frameworks, Libraries, & Technologies: Proficient in React, Redux, Storybook, Node.js, Express, Bootstrap; Experience with NestJS, AWS S3

Databases: Proficient with MongoDB; Experience with SQL

EXPERIENCE

HqO - Software Engineer

Boston, MA | Jun 2021 - Present

- Write code using typescript and modern react with functional components and hooks to develop user interfaces for our resource booking web application
- Create modular react components using custom hooks to manage component logic
- Utilize redux for centralized state management and useState hook for component state
- Fetch data from our REST APIs, process the data when necessary, and display the data in the UI
- Style components according to figma designs using the react styled components library
- Ensure app is performant using memoization via react hooks such as useCallback and useMemo
- Create shared components using storybook with an emphasis on component reusability and extensibility
- Occasionally contribute back end code, including database migrations, API updates, and business logic
- Demonstrate our products at company-wide meetings, always with an emphasis on highlighting customer value and user experience
- Contribute meaningful ideas during product and UX planning meetings
- Perform regular code reviews with an emphasis on correctness and maintainability
- Perform regular product testing to ensure that the product behaves as expected
- Mentor and provide training to junior software engineers on the team
- Write tech plans, test plans, and jira tickets
- Periodically fill in for team lead and run our daily standups
- Contribute to our company blog, most recently writing a post about company culture & workplace experience

JoyList - Founder

Boston, MA | 2020 - 2021

- Conceptualized JoyList as an app to help users curate and exchange lists of their favorite movies, shows, books, restaurants, and more, with close friends and family
- Built an early prototype using the mongo express react node (MERN) stack with AWS S3 for image storage
- Wrote the product specifications with an emphasis on user experience, helped create the design system, and hired a software
 development team to build the web and mobile apps
- Released JoyList on the Apple App Store and Google Play Store and reached hundreds of registered users

Alexion Pharmaceuticals – Senior Manager, Global Clinical Operations Boston, MA | 2020 – 2021 & 2014-2019

- Joined in 2014 as an associate manager focused on providing operational support to the project lead, eventually being promoted two levels to senior manager
- As a senior manager in the late phase department, led cross-functional teams with the goal of ensuring continued post-trial access to Alexion medical treatments for clinical trial patients located in North America, Europe, and Asia
- Developed a vast patient database using smartsheet, built custom reports based on stakeholder needs, and designed dashboards showing key metrics and data visualizations used for reporting to senior management
- Designed an algorithm using python which enabled study teams to quickly generate budget ranges based on a number of requirements, including the fair market value for a given procedure, the complexity of the procedure, and volume of data recorded

General Assembly – Bootcamp Student Boston, MA | 2019 - 2019

- Individually developed 2 full stack applications and 1 client application using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Express, MongoDB,
 Node.js, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, and AWS S3
- Wrote user stories, sketched wireframes, and created entity relationship diagrams for each project
- Collaborated on a full stack project with 3 other developers using git for version control, creating separate branches per feature, writing clear commit messages, and submitting pull requests
- Learned to debug efficiently using the JavaScript console and developer tools, as well as the importance of reading documentation and searching forums for solutions to commonly encountered problems
- Successfully completed regular coding challenges, diagnostic assessments, and whiteboarding exercises